export const Turkish1aQ = [
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-a.mp3",
        options: ["a", "e", "u", "o"],
        correctAnswer: "a",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3",
        options: ["b", "p", "t", "v"],
        correctAnswer: "b",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-d.mp3",
        options: ["d", "t", "j", "l"],
        correctAnswer: "d",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-e.mp3",
        options: ["e", "i", "ö", "u"],
        correctAnswer: "e",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-f.mp3",
        options: ["f", "v", "b", "p"],
        correctAnswer: "f",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-g.mp3",
        options: ["g", "k", "j", "c"],
        correctAnswer: "g",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-h.mp3",
        options: ["h", "c", "t", "p"],
        correctAnswer: "h",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-i.mp3",
        options: ["i", "u", "e", "ü"],
        correctAnswer: "i",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-iu.mp3",
        options: ["ı", "u", "a", "ü"],
        correctAnswer: "ı",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-k.mp3",
        options: ["k", "g", "ğ", "c"],
        correctAnswer: "k",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-o.mp3",
        options: ["o", "u", "ö", "ı"],
        correctAnswer: "o",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-oe.mp3",
        options: ["ö", "u", "e", "i"],
        correctAnswer: "ö",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-u.mp3",
        options: ["u", "a", "ı", "o"],
        correctAnswer: "u",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Which letter makes this sound?",
        media: "http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ue.mp3",
        options: ["ü", "u", "ı", "o"],
        correctAnswer: "ü",
        qType: 'listening-multi'
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-a.mp3", "a"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-e.mp3", "e"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-i.mp3", "i"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-u.mp3", "u"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-d.mp3", "d"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3", "b"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-k.mp3", "k"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-g.mp3", "g"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-f.mp3", "f"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-h.mp3", "h"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3", "b"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-e.mp3", "e"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-oe.mp3", "ö"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ue.mp3", "ü"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-iu.mp3", "ı"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-o.mp3", "o"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-k.mp3", "k"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3", "b"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-g.mp3", "g"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-f.mp3", "f"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        question: "Match the letters to the sounds:",
        pairs: [
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-a.mp3", "a"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-k.mp3", "k"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-h.mp3", "h"],
            ["http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-iu.mp3", "ı"],
            
        ],
        qType: 'listening-matching',
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-a.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'a'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-b.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'b'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-d.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'd'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-e.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'e'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-f.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'f'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-g.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'g'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-h.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'h'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-i.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'i'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-iu.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ı'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-k.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'k'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-o.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'o'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-oe.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ö'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-u.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'u'
    },
    {
        qType: 'listening-typing',
        question: 'Type the letter you hear!',
        media: 'http://app.worldlexicon.org/src/audio/tur/tur-ue.mp3',
        correctAnswer: 'ü'
    },
];



const shuffleArray = (array) => {
    const shuffledArray = [...array];
    for (let i = shuffledArray.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
        const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
        [shuffledArray[i], shuffledArray[j]] = [shuffledArray[j], shuffledArray[i]];
    }
    return shuffledArray;
};

const shuffleOptions = (questions) => {
    return questions.map((question) => {
        if (question.qType === 'listening-multi') {
            return { ...question, options: shuffleArray(question.options) };
        } else if (question.qType === 'listening-matching') {
            return { ...question, pairs: shuffleArray(question.pairs) };
        } else {
            return question; // Handle other question types if needed
        }
    });
};

export const shuffledTurkish1aQ = shuffleArray(shuffleOptions(Turkish1aQ));